thefrugaltoad.com 2019-07-07

# Privacy Policy

**Last Updated November 17th, 2018**

This privacy policy defines how we collect, use and share informations when you make the decision to use our services. For the purpose of our Privacy Policy, the term “Your Information” encompases any information about you which may be deemed confidential that you provide to Modest Money through any means of communication.

 **How We Collect Information**

Information including your name, email address, address and any other personal information may be collected under the following circumstances…

-When forms are filled out through our services,

-When you sign up for newsletters or any other materials through our services.

-When you provide information through a third party.

-When you communicate with us and request information.

-When you participate in marketing initiatives including, but not limited to contests, events and promotions.

-When you participate in forums or other user generated content through our services.

 **Information Provided By Third Parties**

In an attempt to provide the best quality service available, we may collect information from third parties such as blogs, websites and social platforms in order to learn more about you and the rest of our audience.

 **Cookies**

We and other third parties use various technologies to collect and store information when you use our services. This includes the use of cookies, pixel tags or other anonymous identifiers.

The information collected through these technologies, standing alone, cannot be used to determine your identity. Such information may, however, be combined in a way that makes it become personal information (e.g. information that can identify you). If this happens, we will treat the combined information as personal information. Please note that, in most cases, you can remove or block cookies by using the settings in your browser, but doing so may affect your ability to use our Services.

The use of tracking technologies by our service providers, technology partners or other Third Party assets (such as social media) on the Services is not covered by our Privacy Policy. These Third Parties may use cookies, clear gifs, images, and scripts to help them better manage their content on our Services. We do not have access or control over these technologies.

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by TheFrugalToad.com and our partners, affiliates, or analytics or service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

We use local storage objects (LSOs) such as HTML5 to store content information and preferences. Third Parties, with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity, use LSOs such as HTML5 to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs. To manage Flash LSOs please click here: [ _http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html  _](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html).

 **How We Use Your Information**

We may make Use of Your Information for various lawful business purposes. Among others, these purposes may include using Your Information to:

  * Engage in customer support. For example, we might confirm and complete transactions requested by you, verify information you provide to us and provide you with administrative notices.
  *   * Resolve problems and disputes, and engage in other legal and security matters. For example, we may use Your Information to comply with, monitor compliance with and enforce this Privacy Policy, and any other applicable agreements and policies, meet other legal and regulatory requirements, and to protect the security and integrity of our Services.

 **How We Disclose Information**

 **General Disclosure of Your Information**

We will share your personal information with Third Parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy. We do not sell your personal information to Third Parties.

We may disclose Your Information:

  * To any person who, in our reasonable judgment, is authorized to receive Your Information as your agent, including as a result of your business dealings with that person (i.e., your attorney);
  * To our third-party vendors so that they may provide support for our internal and business operations, including for the handling of data processing, data verification, data storage, surveys, research, internal marketing, delivery of promotional, marketing and transaction materials, and our Services’ maintenance and security. These companies are authorized to Use Your Information only as necessary to provide these services to us and are contractually obligated to keep Your Information confidential;
  * To Third Parties such as credit card providers when you use our Services to request a quote, services, or information from one or more of those Third Parties such as by clicking “get your approval” or other similar buttons at the end of a form;
  * To Third Parties when you engage in certain activities through our Services that are sponsored by them, such as purchasing products or services offered by a Third Party, electing to receive information or communications from a Third Party, or electing to participate in programs sponsored, in whole or in part, by a Third Party. When we disclose Your Information to these Third Parties, Your Information will become subject to the information use and sharing practices of the Third Party, and the Third Party will not be restricted by this Privacy Policy with respect to its use and further sharing of Your Information;
  * To Third Parties that are interested in contacting you or providing offers to you that may be related to our Services or about products or services you may find of interest; If you do not want us to share your personal information with these companies, contact us at thefrugaltoad@gmail.com.
  * As required by law or ordered by a court, regulatory, or administrative agency;

  * As we deem necessary, in our sole discretion, if we believe that you are violating any applicable law, rule or regulation, or are otherwise interfering with another’s rights or property, including, without limitation, our rights or property;
  * If requested by authorities in the event of any act of terrorism or instance of local, regional or national emergency;
  * To enforce our this Privacy Policy, and any other applicable agreements and policies;
  * To enforce or protect our rights;
  * In connection with a Business Transfer, as defined below (see Business Transfers below); and
  * To our affiliated companies (e.g. companies under common control or management with us).

If you do not want Your Information shared as described above, then you should not provide us with Your Information.

Requests for Approvals and Services from Third Party Service Providers

As noted above, we may share Your Information with Requested Service Providers when you use our Services to request an approval, services or information from one or more Third Parties (a “Request”). IF YOU SUBMIT A REQUEST, REQUESTED SERVICE PROVIDERS MAY CONTACT YOU DIRECTLY WITH QUOTES VIA MAIL, TELEPHONE, TEXT MESSAGE, FAX, EMAIL AND OTHER MEANS OF COMMUNICATION. YOU MAY RECEIVE TELEMARKETING CALLS AS A CONSEQUENCE OF SUBMITTING A REQUEST THROUGH OUR SERVICES, EVEN IF YOU ARE ON THE NATIONAL DO NOT CALL REGISTRY OR ANY OTHER DO NOT CALL REGISTRY.

If you are matched with Third Party Service Providers, you expressly consent to those Service Providers conducting any research necessary to provide you with quotes for your Request. Third Party Service Providers may need to share Your Information to conduct such research. As an example, if you request approval for a credit card, consumer reports may be ordered in connection with your application. Such reports may provide information that may assist in determining eligibility for insurance and the interest rate you may be charged for the card. Consumer reports may also be used for updates, renewal or extensions of this insurance. In addition, card issuers may use Third Parties in connection with the development of a “credit score” for you. If you do not want Third Party Service Providers to conduct necessary research to provide you with an approval for your Request, then you should not submit a Request.

Please note that if you submit a Request through our Services and we share Your Information as described above in connection with your Request, you will not have the opportunity to opt out of the disclosure of Your Information in connection with that Request.

 **Aggregation and De-Personalization**

We may take Your Information and de-personalize it either by combining it with information about other individuals (aggregating Your Information with information about other individuals), or by removing characteristics (such as your name) that make the information personally identifiable to you (de-personalizing Your Information). We reserve the right to share, loan, rent, sell, or otherwise disclose such information to Third Parties at any time, for any lawful purpose, without notice or compensation to you.

 **Sharing with Friends**

If the Services contains any functionality allowing you to send content to a friend, then please be aware that: 1) we may display your email address to your friend; and 2) we may use information you provide about your friend to facilitate the communication and as otherwise set forth in this Privacy Policy. We do not store this information, but use it for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email.

 **Circumvention of Security Measures**  
When you enter sensitive information (such as last four digits of your social security number), we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it.

We cannot ensure that Your Information will only be disclosed as described in this Privacy Policy. No method of transmission or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, and we cannot guarantee absolute security. Additionally, by way of example (without limiting the foregoing), we may be forced to disclose Your Information to the government or Third Parties under certain circumstances, or Third Parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications. Therefore, notwithstanding anything to the contrary within this Privacy Policy, our or any other applicable agreement or policy, you use our Services at your own risk and we do not promise or guarantee, and you should not expect, that Your Information will always remain private. In the event that an unauthorized Third Party compromises our security measures, we will not be responsible for any damages directly or indirectly caused by an unauthorized Third Party’s ability to view, use or disseminate Your information.  
**Business Transfers**

We specifically and expressly reserve the right to disclose, lease, sell, assign or transfer Your Information collected through our Services, and any of our databases, together with any personal information contained in such databases, to Third Parties in connection with a Business Transfer. A “Business Transfer” means a share or asset sale, acquisition, merger, consolidation, reorganization, spin-off, bankruptcy or other corporate change involving us and/or our affiliates, even if the Business Transfer is only being contemplated and regardless of whether the Business Transfer relates to a part or a whole of our business. Nothing in this Privacy Policy is intended to interfere with our ability to transfer all or part of our business, equity, and/or assets (including our Services) to an affiliate or independent Third Party at any time, for any lawful purpose, without compensation to you. If TheFrugalToad.com is involved in a Business Transfer, you will be notified via prominent notice on our website of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.

 **Children’s Information**

You must be at least 15 years of age to register with or use certain portions of the Services. The Services are not intended for children under 15 years of age. No one under 15 years of age may provide any personal information to or on the Services. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 15. If you believe that we may have any information from or about a child, please contact us at thefrugaltoad@gmail.com.

 **Network Advertising**

From time to time, we may participate in or use advertising networks, such as third-party advertising servers, advertising agencies, technology vendors and research firms. We may use these third-party advertising networks for marketing, advertising and promotional purposes, as well as to serve advertisements to you. Advertising networks often gather data about consumers who view advertisements to make inferences about a consumer’s interests and preferences, which enables their computers to deliver advertisements directly targeted to the consumer’s specific interests. This practice is often referred to as “online behavioral advertising.” For example, a third-party advertising network might collect the type of Internet browser you use, the type of computer operating system you use, the domain name of a website you visit, whether or not you visit specific pages of a website, the location of your Internet Service Provider, the date and time of a visit to a website and other interactions between you and a website.

 **User Generated Content**

We offer publicly accessible blogs and other interactive media through our Services. To request removal of Your Information from our blog or community forum, contact us at thefrugaltoad@gmail.com. In some cases, we may not be able to remove Your Information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

 **Your Choices About How We Use and Disclose Your Information**

We strive to provide you with choices regarding the personal information you provide to us. Below are some mechanisms that provide you with control over certain information:

  * Cookies. If you do not wish us to collect cookies, you may set your browser to refuse cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. If you do so, please note that some parts of our Services may then be inaccessible or may not function properly.
  * Email Offers from Us. If you do not wish to receive email offers or newsletters from us, you can opt out of receiving email information from us (other than emails related to the completion of your registration, correction of user data, change of password and other similar communications essential to your transactions through our Services) by using the unsubscribe process at the bottom of the email.

 **Information You Disclose to Third Parties**

You may be presented with an opportunity to receive information and/or marketing offers from Third Parties in connection with our Services. All information you disclose to such Third Parties will be subject to the privacy policy and practices of such Third Parties. We are not responsible for the privacy policies and practices of such Third Parties and, therefore, you should review the privacy policies and practices of such Third Parties prior to disclosing information to them. If you later decide that you no longer want to receive communications from a Third Party, you will need to contact that Third Party directly.

 **Links to Third-Party Websites**

Our Services, as well as the email messages sent with respect to our Services, may contain links or access to websites operated by Third Parties that are beyond our control. For example, if you click to apply for a product such as a credit card through our Services, you may be linked to a third-party website to complete an application. Links or access to Third Parties from our Services are not an endorsement by us of such Third Parties, or their websites, applications, products, services, or practices. We are not responsible for the privacy policy, terms and

conditions, practices or the content of such Third Parties. These Third Parties may send their own cookies to you and independently collect data. If you visit or access a Third-party website, application or other property that is linked or accessed from our Services, we encourage you to read any privacy policies and terms and conditions of that Third Party before providing any personal information. If you have a question about the terms and conditions, privacy policy, practices or contents of a Third Party, please contact the Third Party directly.

 **Third Party Widgets and Plug-ins**

Our Services include social media features, such as the Facebook Like button, links to our various social media pages and widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our Services. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a Third Party or hosted directly through our Services. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

 **Changes to this Privacy Policy**

We reserve the right to update, amend and/or change this Privacy Policy at any time in our sole discretion. Amendments will take effect immediately upon us posting the updated Privacy Policy on our Services. You are encouraged to revisit this Privacy Policy from time to time in order to review any changes that have been made. The date on which this Privacy Policy was last updated will be noted immediately above this Privacy Policy. Your continued access and use of our Services following the posting of any such changes shall automatically be deemed your acceptance of all changes. If we make any material changes to how we use information we have collected from you, we will disclose this by means of a notice on this site prior to the change becoming effective.

 **Contacting Us**

If you have questions or concerns about our privacy practices or wish to make a request regarding Your Information, please contact us at dataprotection@ModestMoney.com.

Special Notification for California Residents — Your California Privacy Rights

Individuals who are residents of California and have provided their personal information to us may request information regarding our disclosures, if any, of their personal information to Third Parties for direct marketing purposes. Such requests must be submitted to us at thefrugaltoad@gmail.com :

California privacy rights requests must include the reference “Request for California Privacy Information” on the subject line and in the body of the message and must include the email address or mailing address, as applicable, for us to send our response. This request may be made no more than once per calendar year. We reserve the right not to respond to requests submitted other than to the address specified above.

If you have any questions regarding the privacy policy of The Frugal Toad then you may contact us at thefrugaltoad at gmail dot com
